solarquotes.com.au 2019-08-05

# Privacy Policy | Solar Quotes | Power, Panels, Rebate, Installers

**The details of our privacy policy are below. But here are our 4  Golden Rules:**

_“If you ask for 1, 2 or 3 quotes (you can choose how many quotes you want), your information will only be provided to a maximum of 1, 2 or 3 solar power companies accordingly, who serve your area. Each installer is only allowed to use your information to give you a solar quote._

_If you check the box saying you are looking for finance we will provide your information to Parker Lane  to contact you about your solar finance options. We will only do this after you submit your request for a quote and you have consented to being contacted by Parker Lane. Parker Lane is a trading name of Upside Downside Pty Ltd Australian Credit License number 482276, and has appointed us as its corporate credit representative. Our credit representative number is 482276_  _. We will receive a fee for a successful referral to Parker Lane  which results in a loan. Parker Lane is required to disclose any fee payable to us in their documentation to you.  _

_We hate spam as much as you do. We will never pass your information on to anyone except the 3 solar installers and Parker Lane unless you give us your explicit permission to do so._

_We will send you emails walking you through the solar buying process, asking you for feedback and may send updates on the solar industry and occasional offers that we think may be of interest to you. Every email will have a prominent unsubscribe link if you don’t want to receive them any more.”_

**And here’s the full monty:**

**PRIVACY POLICY**

1\. We are committed to protecting your privacy. We adhere to the Australian Privacy Principles and other obligations contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). We have set out what information we collect about you when you visit our website and how we use that information below.

2\. “Personal information” is personal data and information we hold which is identifiable as being about an individual. 

3\. This policy governs our treatment of personal information, including information that we gather when you access or use any online service location that posts a link to this Privacy Policy and also applies to your use of our website, products and services (collectively, the “Services”), but not to the practices of companies we don’t own or control, or people that we don’t manage. We gather various types of information from our users, and we use this information for you to interact with our Services, including to personalise, provide, and improve our Services, to allow you to set up a user account and profile, to contact you and allow other users to contact you, to fulfil your requests for certain products and Services, and to analyse how you use the Services. In certain cases, we may also share some personal information with third parties.

**Collection of personal information**

4\. When you visit our website, we may collect certain information for analysis purposes, including—

4.1. how many times you visit our website, what pages you view, and how long you stay on our website;

4.2. details about what kind of browser and other software you are using to visit our website; and

4.3. your IP address.

5\. We may from time to time use web beacons and cookies on our website. Web beacons (also known as web bugs, pixel tags, or clear GIFs) are tiny graphics with a unique identifier that may be included on our services to provide information or communicate with us. Cookies are very small files which a website uses to identify users when a user comes back to the site and to store details about that user’s use of the site. Cookies are not malicious programs that access or damage a user’s computer or device. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but a user can choose to reject cookies by changing the browser settings. However, this may prevent a user from taking full advantage of our website. We may use cookies to:

5.1. enable us to monitor traffic patterns, user actions (like how many people submit a form) and to identify your computer when you return to our website. Cookies do not identify you personally, but they do identify your computer. Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but usually you can alter the settings of your browser to prevent automatic acceptance. If you choose not to receive cookies, you may not be able to use certain features of our website.

5.2. engage in remarketing to market our sites across the web. Users with a remarketing cookie may be targeted across advertising networks to receive relevant advertisements. You may opt out of this ad serving using the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) opt-out page (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>) or you can opt out of just the Google Remarketing program by using the [Google Ad Preference manager](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en) You can also use the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) tool to opt out of the Google Remarketing program.

6\. If you choose to provide us your details using the ‘Get a Quote’ form, we will collect personal information that you provide using that form, including—

6.1. your name, addresses (including personal, postal, and prospective installation addresses), phone number, and e-mail address;

6.2. any other identifying details that you choose to provide to us using the form;

7\. We may collect additional information at other times, including but not limited to, when you provide feedback, or when you provide information about your personal or business affairs, change content or email preferences, respond to surveys and/or promotions.

8\. You generally have the right not to identify yourself when dealing with us where it is lawful and practicable for us to allow it. However, if you choose to do so, we may not be able to provide our Services to you.

9\. If you choose to provide us with a review of our service or of the goods or services you receive from one of a supplier, we may store that review and post it to our website or social media.

10\. We will only collect your personal information by lawful and fair means.

**Holding your personal information**

11\. We may store the personal information that you provide us on servers hosted overseas when carrying out any of the uses described in this Policy. It is impractical to list all the countries in which your personal information, but these include the United States, the United Kingdom and India.

12\. We are committed to ensuring that personal information provided to us is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure information and protect it from misuse, interference, loss and unauthorised access, modification and disclosure. Although we take measures to safeguard against unauthorised disclosures of information, we cannot provide an assurance that in all cases personal information that we collect will not be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

13\. You acknowledge that personal information that you submit through our website or services may become available, via the internet, around the world. The internet is an inherently non-secure medium and we cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of intercepted personal information by others.

**Using and disclosing your personal information**

14\. We use and disclose your personal information to provide you with information, updates, and our Services, including for the purpose of matching you with suitable suppliers. The suppliers who receive your personal information will then contact you with the information that you provided to give you a quote. 

15\. We will also provide your information to Parker Lane to contact you about your solar finance options. You can access Parker Lane’s privacy policy [here](https://www.parkerlane.com.au/privacy). Please note that we do not operate or control the websites of any supplier, and we are not responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to read and understand the privacy policies of any website that collects personal information.

16\. We may, from time to time need to disclose personal information to comply with a legal requirement, such as a law, regulation, court order, subpoena, warrant, in the course of a legal proceeding or in response to a law enforcement agency request.

17\. We may also use personal information to protect our copyright, trademarks, legal rights, property or safety, and that of our customers or third-parties.

18\. If you provide us with your name and e-mail address we will store your name and e-mail address and use it to send you occasional newsletter and servicing emails until such time as you inform us that you want to unsubscribe using the unsubscribe link at the end of every newsletter email. Please note, however, that you may be unable to opt out of some administrative communications that are reasonably necessary to the Services, such as confirmations or service notifications

19\. Except as specified above, we will not, without your permission, sell or otherwise provide your personal information to a third party, or make any other use of your personal information, for any purpose that is not incidental to your use of our website or Services. To avoid doubt, we will never use your personal information for any purpose not listed in this Policy, or that a reasonable person in your position would not expect.

20\. In certain circumstances, we may aggregate the personal information that we store for the purposes of analysis, but, if we do, we will ensure that the information is made anonymous first.

**Requests to access or cease use of personal information**

21\. If you request us not to use personal information in a particular matter or at all, we will take all reasonable steps to comply with your request. However, we may still use your information if—

21.1. we subsequently notify you of the intended use of your information and you consent to that use; or

21.2. we believe that the use of your information is reasonably necessary to assist a law enforcement agency or an agency responsible for government or public security in the performance of its functions; or

21.3. we are required by law to do so.

22\. You are entitled to have access to any of the personal information that you have previously supplied to us and that is in our possession, and you are entitled to change or delete such information except where we are required by law to retain it.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

23\. Please be aware that we may change this Privacy Policy in the future. We may modify this Policy at any time, in our sole discretion and all modifications will be effective immediately upon our posting of the modifications on our website. Please check back from time to time to review our Privacy Policy.

**Contacting us about privacy**

24\. Please refer your privacy queries, requests or complaints to us at www.solarquotes.com.au/contact.php or via email: privacy@solarquotes.com.au or by phone 08 7200 0177 or at our address: 3/39 Grenfell St, Adelaide, SA 5000.

25\. We will consider your question or complaint and respond to you in a reasonable timeframe.

26\. If you are not satisfied with the outcome, then you may contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner:

Office of the Australian Information Commissioner

Website: www.oaic.gov.au

Phone: 1300 363 992

  _Solar Quotes offers services to match Australian based providers with customers in Australia. Our site is not directed to persons in the European Union (EU) and we do not provides services to persons within the EU._

 Peacock Media Group P/L, ACN: 140 645 932

 To get your quotes, please enter your postcode:
